Robert Thorson Papers
© 2008 University of Connecticut
Robert Thorson Papers.
undated, 1851-2005
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Thorson, Robert M., 1951-
4.65 linear feet
Professor of geology and geophysics at the University of Connecticut in Storrs, Thorson holds a joint appointment in anthropology. His current research includes the historical archaeology of New England landscapes and seismic hazards in Seattle. He served as consultant on the development of exhibits at the Mashantucket Pequot Museum in Uncasville, CT.
MSS19990026
Biography
Professor of geology and geophysics at the University of Connecticut in Storrs, Robert Thorson holds a joint appointment in anthropology. His current research includes the historical archaeology of New England landscapes and seismic hazards in Seattle. He served as consultant on the development of exhibits at the Mashantucket Pequot Museum in Uncasville, CT.
Scope and Content
Collection contains copies of articles about and sketches and dummy for Stone Wall Secrets. Research materials created or accumulated by a colleague of Thorson's, Dena Dincauze, in the course of her research and sent to Thorson to document the research.
A subsequent donation includes drafts, correspondence, edited and reviewed copies of Stone by stone and Exploring stone walls.
Arrangement
Series I: Stone wall secrests ( 1998 )
Series II: Research files ( 1851-2005 )
Series III: Stone by stone ( undated, 1989-2002 ) Draft numbering supplied by author.
Series IV: Exploring stone walls ( undated, 2003-2005 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork as well as the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students, etc.]. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Stone wall secrets. Thorson, Robert. Dodd CLC D249
Stone by Stone. Thorson, Robert. Dodd
Exploring stone walls. Thorson, Robert. Dodd A9083
A 3.25 inch floppy disk has been separated for appraisal.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Thorson, Robert M., 1951- --Stone wall secrets.; Thorson, Robert M., 1951- --Stone by stone.; Thorson, Robert M., 1951- --Exploring stone walls.
Subjects:
Stone walls.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Books.; Illustrations.; Photocopies.; Field notes.; Typescripts.
Occupations:
Professor.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated by the author to the University of Connecticut in 1999 and 2005.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: Stone Wall Secrets, 1998
  - Articles, 1998 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Dummy (copy), undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Sketches, undated; (6, copy) (Box 1:, Folder 3)
- Series II: Research files, 1851-2005
  - Amherst, 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography, 1851-1995 (Box 2:, Folder 5)
  - Millis, 1964-2005 (Box 2:, Folder 6)
  - Northfield, 1973-1980 (Box 2:, Folder 7)
- Series III: Stone by Stone, undated, 1989-2002
  - Initial proposal, undated (Box 3:, Folder 8)
  - Draft #1, undated (Box 3:, Folder 9-10)
  - Draft #2, undated (Box 3:, Folder 11-13)
  - Draft #3, undated (Box 3:, Folder 14-15)
  - Draft #4, undated (Box 3:, Folder 16)
  - Draft #5, undated (Box 3:, Folder 17)
  - Draft #6, 1997d (Box 3:, Folder 18)
  - Draft #7 (Jamie review), undated (Box 3:, Folder 19)
  - Draft, 2001 November 20 (Box 3:, Folder 20)
    - Transparencies (Box 6:, Folder 73)
    - Photographs (Box 6:, Folder 74)
  - Draft #8, 2001 December (Box 3:, Folder 21)
  - Draft #9, undated (Box 3:, Folder 22-23)
  - Draft #10, undated (Box 3:, Folder 24)
  - Draft #11, undated (Box 4:, Folder 25-26)
  - Draft #12, undated (Box 4:, Folder 27-28)
  - Draft #13, undated (Box 4:, Folder 29-30)
  - DRaft #14, undated (Box 4:, Folder 31-32)
  - Draft #15, undated (Box 4:, Folder 33-34)
  - Draft #16, undated (Box 4:, Folder 35)
  - Draft #17, undated (Box 4:, Folder 36-37)
  - Draft #18, undated (Box 4:, Folder 38-39)
  - Draft #19, undated (Box 4:, Folder 40-41)
  - Draft #20, undated (Box 4:, Folder 42)
  - Draft #21, undated (Box 4:, Folder 43)
  - Edited, 2001 December 5 (Box 4:, Folder 44-45)
  - Reference and research materials, undated (Box 5:, Folder 46)
  - Notes, 1995 May (Box 5:, Folder 47)
  - Overview, Table of Contents, References, undated, 2001 (Box 5:, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1996-2002 (Box 5:, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence--editor, 2002 (Box 5:, Folder 50)
  - A Guide for Authors, Houghton Mifflin, 1989 (Box 5:, Folder 51)
  - Clipping, 1991 (Box 5:, Folder 52)
- Series IV: Exploring stone walls, undated, 2003-2005
  - Materials, undated (Box 5:, Folder 53)
  - Notes, undated (Box 5:, Folder 54)
  - Notes, 2003 (Box 5:, Folder 55)
  - Draft, 2003 August 4 (Box 5:, Folder 56)
  - Draft, 2003 September 12 (Box 5:, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence, 2003-2005 (Box 5:, Folder 58)
  - Draft, 2003 July - October (Box 5:, Folder 59)
  - Draft, 2003 September 26 (Box 5:, Folder 60)
  - Draft, 2003 October 1 (Box 5:, Folder 61)
  - Field guide, 2003 November 4 (Box 5:, Folder 62-63)
  - Draft, 2004 January 10 (Box 5:, Folder 64)
  - Draft, 2004 January 14 (Box 5:, Folder 65)
  - Draft--edited, 2004 February 1 (Box 5:, Folder 66)
  - Review copy (Rufus Frost), 2004 February - April (Box 5:, Folder 67-68)
  - Field guide, 2004 February 1 (Box 5:, Folder 69-70)
  - Edited draft (annotated photocopy), 2004 June 2 (Box 5:, Folder 71-72)